Guide to the University of Pittsburgh Archives Information Files, c. 1900-present UA.Info.Files
ULS Archives & Special Collections
- O
  - Office for Educational Research
  - Office of Business Affairs; SEE Business Affairs
  - Office of Conference Coordinator; SEE Conference Coordination, Office of
  - Office of Management Information and Policy Analysis; SEE Management Information and Policy Analysis, Office of
  - Office of Public Affairs; SEE Public Affairs, Vice Chancellor for
  - Office of Research; SEE Research, Office of
  - Office of Risk Management
  - Office Services; SEE Business Affairs
  - Ombudsman; SEE Personnel
  - Omicron Delta Kappa
  - Open House
  - "Open" University
  - Operation Jump Start (1992-present)
  - Operations, Office for; SEE Business Affairs
  - Oral History Program
  - Organization Charts
  - Organization of Arab Students
  - Osteoporosis; SEE ALSO RG 90/42/3-B
  - Overseas Program in Educational Studies
  - Owl; SEE Pitt Publications
- P
  - Pan Hellenic; SEE Fraternities
  - Panther Hollow Research Park; SEE ALSO Oakland Corporation
  - Parent's Council
  - Parent's Weekend
  - Parking; SEE ALSO Police Department
  - Parran Lecture Series
  - Patent Policy of University
  - Payroll Department
  - PC Support and Service Center
  - Peace Corps (Intercultural Training Consultants, 1968)
  - Pennsylvania Art Collection; SEE Gimbel's Pennsylvania Art Collection
  - Pennsylvania Educational Research Association
  - Pennsylvania Ethnic Heritages Studies Center; SEE ALSO Ethnic Studies
  - Pennsylvania Forensic and Musical League; SEE RG 90/9/3
  - Pennsylvania Hall
  - Pennsylvania (History)
  - Pennsylvania Right-To-Know Act
  - Pennsylvania State Education Association
  - Pennsylvania Way
  - Pershing Rifles
  - Personal Files; SEE ALSO Administrative Officers; Alumni- Biography; Board of Trustees- Biography; Faculty
  - Personnel; SEE ALSO Affirmative Action Program; Employment; Insurance; Human Resources, Office of Assistant Vice Chancellor
  - Personnel Job Openings
  - Physical Plant
  - PIRG; SEE Public Interest Research Group
  - Pitcairn-Crabbe Foundation Lectures; SEE Lectures
  - Pitt Abroad; SEE Cultural and Educational Exchange Program; Travel Service
  - Pitt Caucus; SEE Pennsylvania State Education Association
  - Pitt-China Exchange; SEE China-Pitt Exchange
  - Pitt Club; SEE ALSO Faculty Club
  - Pitt Community Calendar
  - Pitt Hillel (Periodical); SEE Religious Activities
  - Pitt Imprint; SEE RG 90/29/7-B
  - Pitt Informal Program; SEE ALSO Schools- College of General Studies- Informal Courses- Bulletins; Schools- College of General Studies- Informal Courses- Lectures and Programs
  - Pitt Library School Bookmark; SEE RG 90/29/7-B
  - Pitt Panther (statue and mascot), History of
  - Pitt Parents Association
  - Pitt Players and Summer Pitt Players
  - Pitt Preview; SEE Freshman- Applications and Information
  - Pitt Professional Union (merged with the American Association of University Professors to become United Faculty in 1982)
  - Pitt Program Council
  - Pitt Publications
  - Pitt Publications- Finance Campaign Brochures; SEE Finance
  - Pitt Pulse, December 2013
  - Pitt Reports to Business and Industry
  - Pitt Shop, The
  - Pitt Town Meeting, SEE Assemblies
  - Pitt Travel and Tours
  - Pitt Wildwood Club
  - Pitt Young Socialist Alliance
  - Pittiquette; SEE RG 55/4/2; RG 55/16/2
  - Pittsburgh Bicentennial
  - Pittsburgh Cancer Institute
  - Pittsburgh Chamber Music Society
  - Pittsburgh Council on Higher Education
  - Pittsburgh Council for International Visitors
  - Pittsburgh Regional Inter-American Center
  - Pittsburgh Regional Library Center
  - Pittsburgh Research Institute for Studies in Marketing
  - Pittsburgh Supercomputing Center (PSC)
  - Pittsburgh, University- History; SEE University- History
  - Pittsburgh University Research Center; SEE University of Pittsburgh Applied Research Center (U-PARC)
  - Placement Service; SEE University Counseling and Placement Service
  - Planning; SEE ALSO RG 46- Office; RG 0/2/1- University; RG 3/1/0- Provost
  - Planning and Budgeting System, 1992
  - Plant Services and Building Maintenance Division; SEE Physical Plant
  - Plant Utilization and Planning Committee
  - PM Series
  - Poetry
  - Police Department
  - Poor Peoples Campaign
  - Population Study (Graduate School of Public Health)
  - Post-Baccalaureate Educational Services Office
  - Post-Doctoral Study
  - Posvar, Wesley; SEE Chancellor- Posvar, Wesley
  - "The Premedical Student;" SEE Students (On Campus)
  - Presbyterian Hospital
  - President, Search for
  - President (University)
  - Press-Bee News; SEE University Health Center
  - Price, Gwilym A.; SEE Schools- Engineering
  - Primate Research Laboratory
  - Prism (Pitt's Real Time Integrated Solutions for Management)
  - Prison Program (General Studies); SEE Western Penitentiary
  - Procurement and Materials Management
  - Professional Center
  - Program in Industrial Civilization
  - Program in the Philosophy of Science
  - Programs- Miscellaneous
  - Programs- Musical and Literary
  - Progress Report on Year-Round Education; SEE Trimester Plan
  - Progressive Pitt Trustees
  - Project Bridge
  - Project Talent News
  - Provost
  - Provost's Advisory Committee on Women's Concerns; SEE Provost
  - PSEA; SEE Pennsylvania State Education Association
  - PSEA/NEA-Pitt (Pennsylvania State Education Association and National Education Association, University of Pittsburgh)
  - Psychoeducational Clinic
  - Public Affairs, Vice Chancellor for
  - Public Interest Research Group
  - Public Relations, Office of; SEE Information Service (News and Publications)
  - Public Safety, Department of; SEE ALSO Police Department
  - Public Service
  - Publications, Student; SEE Pitt Publications
  - Publications, University; SEE Pitt Publications
  - Purchases and Office Service Division; SEE ALSO Business Affairs
  - Pymatuning Laboratory of Ecology
- Q
  - Quality Circles
- R
  - R.O.T.C.; SEE ALSO Military Department
  - Race Desegregation Assistance Center; SEE Desegregation and Conflict Center
  - Radiation Research Center in Western Pennsylvania
  - Racial Crisis; SEE ALSO University Committee on Racial Crisis
  - Radio
  - Rank, National
  - Regional Campuses
  - Regional Campuses- Bradford
  - Regional Campuses- Greensburg
  - Regional Campuses- Johnstown
  - Regional Campuses- Titusville
  - Regional Commission on Education Coordination
  - Regional Economic Studies, Center for; SEE RG 15/7
  - Regional Economy (Impact of Pitt)
  - Regional Medical Program; SEE Western Pennsylvania Regional Medical Program
  - Regional Planning
  - Regional Programs
  - Registrar
  - Regulations
  - Religion (Interdepartmental Major); SEE Interdepartmental Majors
  - Religion in Life; SEE Conferences
  - Religious Activities; SEE ALSO Heinz Memorial Chapel; University Chaplains
  - Repertory Theatre
  - Research
  - Research- Medical; SEE Medical Research
  - Research, Office of (established 1976)
  - Research Bureau for Retail Training
  - Residence Houses; SEE Dormitories
  - Residence Life, Office of
  - Resident Student Association; SEE Dormitories
  - Resuscitation Research Center
  - Retirement
  - Richard King Mellon Foundation
  - Ridesharing (UHCP/Pitt Ridesharing Office)
  - Ridgway (Matthew B.) Center for International Security Studies
  - River Communities Project
  - Robert Bruce Society; SEE Annual Giving Fund
  - Rocky Dell Excavation, North Park; SEE Schools- Arts and Sciences- Department of Anthropology
  - Ruskin, The; SEE Housing
  - Russian and East European Studies- Announcements and Miscellaneous
  - Russian and East European Studies- Newsletter and Brochures
- S
  - Safety Policy
  - Salk Hall
  - Scaife Hall
  - Schenley Apartments
  - Schenley Hall (Hotel)
  - Scholar's Day Assemblies; SEE Assemblies- Scholar's Day
  - Scholarship Pageant
  - Scholarships
  - Schools; SEE Downtown Division; Erie Center; Johnstown Center
  - Schools- Arts and Sciences (established 1969)
  - Schools- Arts and Sciences- Administration of Justice
  - Schools- Arts and Sciences- Department of Anthropology; SEE ALSO RG 90/8/1
  - Schools- Arts and Sciences- Department of Biochemistry
  - Schools- Arts and Sciences- Biological Sciences; SEE ALSO Pymatuning Laboratory of Ecology
  - Schools- Arts and Sciences- Department of Biology
  - Schools- Arts and Sciences- Department of Biophysics; SEE ALSO RG 90/8/6
  - Schools- Arts and Sciences- Department of Black Studies
  - Schools- Arts and Sciences- Department of Chemistry; SEE ALSO RG 90/8/8
  - Schools- Arts and Sciences- Department of Classics
  - Schools- Arts and Sciences- Department of Communications
  - Schools- Arts and Sciences- Department of Computer Science
  - Schools- Arts and Sciences- Department of Crystallography
  - Schools- Arts and Sciences- Department of Earth and Planetary Sciences
  - Schools- Arts and Sciences- Department of Economics
  - Schools- Arts and Sciences- Department of English
  - Schools- Arts and Sciences- Department of Film Studies
  - Schools- Arts and Sciences- Department of Fine Arts
  - Schools- Arts and Sciences- Department of French and Italian Languages and Literature
  - Schools- Arts and Sciences- Department of Geography
  - Schools- Arts and Sciences- Department of Geology
  - Schools- Arts and Sciences- Department of Germanic Languages and Literature
  - Schools- Arts and Sciences- Department of Hispanic Languages and Literature
  - Schools- Arts and Sciences- Department of History- Department Newsletter (Historical Methods Newsletter)
  - Schools- Arts and Sciences- Department of History and Philosophy of Science
  - Schools- Arts and Sciences- Department of Jewish Studies
  - Schools- Arts and Sciences- Department of Linguistics, General
  - Schools- Arts and Sciences- Department of Mathematics
  - Schools- Arts and Sciences- Department of Modern Languages (NDEA), French, Spanish
  - Schools- Arts and Sciences- Department of Music
  - Schools- Arts and Sciences- Department of Philosophy
  - Schools- Arts and Sciences- Department of Physics and Astronomy (established 1975)
  - Schools- Arts and Sciences- Department of Political Science
  - Schools- Arts and Sciences- Department of Psychology
  - Schools- Arts and Sciences- Department of Religious Studies
  - Schools- Arts and Sciences- Department of Slavic Language and Literature
  - Schools- Arts and Sciences- Department of Sociology
  - Schools- Arts and Sciences- Department of Speech and Theatre Arts (through 1982); SEE ALSO University Theatre, The
  - Schools- Arts and Sciences- Department of Studio Arts
  - Schools- Arts and Sciences- Department of Theatre Arts (after 1982)
  - Schools- Arts and Sciences- Department of Urban Studies
  - Schools- Arts and Sciences- Speech and Hearing Center
  - Schools- Business Administration; SEE Schools- Graduate School of Business
  - Schools- College of Business Administration
  - Schools- College of General Studies
  - Schools- College of General Studies- Career Development
  - Schools- College of General Studies- Community Educational Services
  - Schools- College of General Studies- Computer Learning Center
  - Schools- College of General Studies- Evening Classes (1958-1973)
  - Schools- College of General Studies- External Studies Program
  - Schools- College of General Studies- Informal Courses- Bulletins; SEE ALSO Pitt Informal Program
  - Schools- College of General Studies- Informal Courses- Lectures and Programs (1964-1973); SEE ALSO Pitt Informal Program; Schools- Late Afternoon, Evening and Saturday
  - Schools- Dental Medicine; SEE Schools- Dentistry
  - Schools- Dentistry
  - Schools- Dentistry- Dental Assistant/Oral Hygiene Program
  - Schools- Division of Humanities; SEE RG 90/4/3
  - Schools- Division of Natural Sciences; SEE 90/4/2
  - Schools- Division of Social Sciences; SEE 90/4/4
  - Schools- Education
  - Schools- Education- Department of Health, Physical and Recreational Education
  - Schools- Education- Department of Religion and Religious Education
  - Schools- Education- Department of Special Education
  - Schools- Education- Educational Placement Office
  - Schools- Education- Falk School; SEE Falk School
  - Schools- Education- General Assistance CTRON School Desegregation
  - Schools- Education- Institute for Higher Education (NDEA)
  - Schools- Education- International and Development Education Program
  - Schools- Education- Research and Field Services
  - Schools- Education- Western Pennsylvania Education Conference- Engineering
  - Schools- Engineering
  - Schools- Graduate School; SEE Graduate Programs; RG 90/3 for 1913-1956
  - Schools- Graduate School of Business (includes conferences); SEE ALSO Management Research Center
  - Schools- Graduate School of Health Professions
  - Schools- Graduate School of Public Health
  - Schools- Graduate School of Public and International Affairs; SEE ALSO Institute for Local Government
  - Schools- Graduate School of Retailing
  - Schools- Graduate School of Library and Information Science; SEE Schools- Library and Information Science
  - Schools- Health and Rehabilitation Sciences (name changed from Health Related Professions 2/4/1992)
  - Schools- Health Professions
  - Schools- Health Related Professions (established July 1969); SEE ALSO Schools- Health and Rehabilitation Sciences
  - Schools- Information Science; SEE ALSO Schools- Library and Information Sciences before 1996
  - Schools- Information Science- Society of American Archivists, Student Chapter
  - Schools- Late Afternoon, Evening and Saturday
  - Schools- Law
  - Schools- Liberal Arts; SEE RG 90/2
  - Schools- Library and Information Sciences; SEE ALSO Schools- Information Sciences after 1996
  - Schools- Medicine
  - Schools- Medicine- Addison H. Gibson Laboratory
  - Schools- Nursing
  - Schools- Pharmacy
  - Schools- The Professions
  - Schools- Social Work and Library
  - Schools- Urban Studies Program
  - Schools and Scholarship Weekend
  - Science Booklist; SEE University Library System
  - Science Technology Library (City); SEE Metropolitan Science-Technology Library
  - Science-Technology Library Pitt; SEE University Library System
  - Science Writing Program
  - Sea Semester; SEE Semester at Sea
  - Seal, University; SEE ALSO Photo file, Miscellaneous Seals
  - Secretary of the University; SEE Administrative Officers
  - Security Department; SEE Police Department
  - Seismological Observatory
  - Semester at Sea
  - Seminars
  - Senate; SEE University Senate
  - Senior Coronation; SEE Commencement Coronation
  - Sexual Assault Service
  - Sexual Harassment; SEE Affirmative Action Program
  - Shakespeare Quadricentennial Celebration
  - Sick Leave; SEE Health Benefits
  - Slavic Advisory Council, 606 Bruce Hall
  - Slavic Club
  - Small Business Center; SEE Schools- Graduate School of Business
  - Smoking; SEE ALSO Affirmative Action Program
  - Social and Urban Research, University Center for; SEE University Center for Social and Urban Research
  - Social Science Information Center
  - Social Sciences Information Utilization Library; SEE University Center for International Studies
  - Songs; SEE Music- Songs of the University of Pittsburgh
  - Sororities; SEE Fraternities
  - Space Management, Office of
  - Space Planning; SEE Physical Plant
  - Space Research Coordination Center
  - Speakers Bureau
  - Special Events Office
  - Special Programs Office
  - Special Seminars, Office of
  - Speeches; SEE Addresses
  - Stadium
  - Staff (material that applies to all University Personnel); SEE Personnel
  - Staff Advisory Board (before 1981); SEE ALSO Staff Association Council (after 1981)
  - Staff Association Council (formerly Staff Advisory Board; name changed in 1981)
  - Staff Ombudsman; SEE Personnel
  - State-Pitt Relationship; SEE ALSO Commonwealth Relations
  - Starzl (Thomas E.) Transplantation Institute
  - Staunton Clinic
  - Stephen Foster Memorial
  - Stone Quarry, The
  - Strategy 21
  - Student Activities
  - Student Affairs, Office of
  - Student Aid
  - Student Employment; SEE RG 55/14/2
  - Student Government
  - Student Health Services
  - Student Movements
  - Student Publications; SEE Pitt Publications
  - Student Records; SEE Registrar
  - Student Union
  - Student Union Assemblies; SEE Assemblies- Student Union
  - Student Volunteer Outreach (formerly Center for Public Community Service, part of Office of Student Activities)
  - Students (On Campus)
  - Students, Graduate
  - Studio Theatre; SEE University Theatre, The
  - Study Abroad (Opportunities from various departments and schools); SEE ALSO Cultural and Educational Exchange Program
  - Summer Sessions; SEE ALSO Regional Campuses- Bradford; Chautauqua
  - Supplies; SEE Property and Supplies
  - Surface Science Center
- T
  - Tap Day Exercises (discontinued 1971); SEE RG 0/10/7
  - Teaching Assistants, Teaching Fellows, Graduate Assistants
  - Teaching Evaluation; SEE ALSO Academic Integrity
  - Technology Center
  - Technology Transfer Program
  - Telecommunications
  - Teleconferences
  - Telephones
  - Television
  - Tenure; SEE ALSO Provost; University Senate
  - Thackery Hall
  - Theatre 11; SEE University Theatre, The
  - Three Rivers Press; SEE University Press
  - Three Rivers Shakespeare Festival
  - Time Schedule of Classes; SEE Downtown Division; Schools- Medicine
  - Tours
  - Tower, The; SEE Medical Center
  - Trademark Licensing Program
  - Transplants
  - Travel Service; SEE ALSO Cultural and Educational Exchange Program
  - Treasurer
  - Trees Gymnasium; SEE RG 13/37
  - Trimester Plan
  - Tri-State Area School Study Council
  - Trustees; SEE Board of Trustees
  - Tuition
  - 2000 (year)
- U
  - Undergraduate Women's Union
  - Unions; SEE ALSO Pennsylvania State Education Association; Pitt Professional Union; United Faculty
  - UCEP; SEE University Challenge for Excellence Program
  - United Faculty (established 1982); SEE ALSO Pitt Professional Union
  - United Fund Campaign
  - United Way; SEE United Fund Campaign
  - University Administrative Officers; SEE Administrative Officers
  - University and City Ministries
  - University Archives
  - University Art Gallery; SEE ALSO Art Exhibitions
  - University Center for Instructional Resources (UCIR)
  - University Center for International Studies (includes East Asian Studies Program; absorbed International Studies Program and International Studies Association); SEE ALSO Cultural and Educational Exchange Program
  - University Center for Social and Urban Research
  - University Challenge for Excellence Program
  - University Chaplains
  - University Committee for Women's Rights
  - University Committee on Racial Crisis
  - University-Community Educational Program (established June 1968)
  - University Council for Early Childhood Programs
  - University Council on Urban Programs (1967-present)
  - University Counsel
  - University Counseling and Placement Service (established 1976); SEE ALSO University Counseling and Student Development Center
  - University Counseling Center (merged with Placement Service in 1976); SEE ALSO University Counseling and Student Development Center
  - University Counseling and Student Development Center (established 1979)
  - University Editor (1926-1930); SEE Administrative Officers
  - University Employee Assistance Program
  - University Health Center
  - University History; SEE ALSO RG 0/3-A for 1781-1985
  - University Honors College
  - University Library System
  - University Library System- Darlington Memorial Library
  - University Library System- Hillman Library
  - University Major Events Calendar; SEE Calendar
  - University News and Publications Office; SEE Information Services
  - University of Pittsburgh Applied Research Center (U-PARC)
  - University of Pittsburgh Association (name change effective 4/30/1976); SEE ALSO Women's Association, University of Pittsburgh (after 9/1/1979 name changed to Women's Association of the University of Pittsburgh)
  - University of Pittsburgh Book Center; SEE Book Stores
  - University of Pittsburgh Students for Conservative Action
  - University Planning and Budget Committee
  - University of Pittsburgh Cancer Institute
  - University of Pittsburgh Trust
  - University Press
  - University Priorities and Budget Committee
  - University Publications (Periodicals, Newsletters); SEE Pitt Publications
  - University Research Council
  - University Science Center
  - University Senate
  - University Space Allocation Committee
  - University Speech Clinic
  - University Spoon
  - University Theatre, The; SEE ALSO Pitt Players; Schools- Arts and Sciences- Department of Speech and Theatre Arts; Schools- Arts and Sciences- Department of Theatre Arts
  - University Times
  - University Travel Service; SEE Travel Service
  - University Union; SEE Student Union
  - University-Urban Interface Program (report on "The Impact of the University of Pittsburgh on the Local Economy," April, 1972)
  - University Wellness Program
  - UP Gallery
  - UPMC Health System
  - Urban and Community Services, Office of
  - Urban Programs; SEE University Council on Urban Programs; Urban and Community Services, Office of
  - USAir Flight 427
- V
  - Van de Graaf Laboratory
  - Varsity Letter Club
  - Veterans
  - Vice Provost for Research and Graduate Studies
  - Volunteer Pool
- W
  - War Activities (World War I and II); SEE ALSO University Newsletter in RG 55/3-B
  - Watson School of Physiatrics
  - Wedgewater Plates
  - Well's Report; SEE Ford Foundation Report
  - Western Penitentiary
  - Western Pennsylvania Advanced Technology Center
  - Western Pennsylvania Gerontology Center
  - Western Pennsylvania Regional Medical Program
  - Western Psychiatric Institute and Clinic
  - Western Psychiatric Institute and Clinic Library
  - Western Reserve Historical Society
  - Western University of Pennsylvania Miscellany
  - What's Happening at the Health Center; SEE University Health Center
  - William Pitt Debating Union; SEE Debating
  - William Pitt Union; SEE Student Union
  - Women
  - Women's Choral; SEE Musical Clubs
  - Women's Studies Program; SEE ALSO Pittsburgh Council on Higher Education for PCHE Women's Studies Communication
  - Women's Association of the University of Pittsburgh; SEE ALSO University of Pittsburgh Association
  - Women's Center (before September 1972 called Advisory Council on Women's Opportunities)
  - Women in the Arts Conference (March 28-30, 1980)
  - Women's Recreation Association; SEE Women
  - Women's Self Government Association (WSGA); SEE RG 55/4/2; RG 55/16/2
  - Woods, George; SEE Chancellor- Woods, George
  - Workshops
  - Writers' Conference
  - Wyoming Land Donation
- X
  - X-Ray Crystallographic Laboratory; SEE Schools- Arts and Sciences- Department of Physics and Astronomy
- Y
  - Young Men's Christian Association